Emmalee E Barnett

emmerz6949@gmail.com • 706-538-8537 Portfolio: https://emmerz6949.github.io/backwards-bee-developing

GitHub: https://github.com/Emmerz6949

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/emmalee-barnett-49900063

SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer with a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from Johns Hopkins University. During the time earning the certificate acquired skills in the following: React.js, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, Command Line, Git, and more. Also worked on many projects both individually and as part of a team (see Projects). Known to be a team player and passionate about web development.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- React.js
- Node.js
- MySQL
- MongoDB
- HTML5

- CSS3
- JavaScript
- Express.js
 - Command Line
- Git
- and more...

PROJECTS

Employee Directory

GitHub Repository: https://github.com/Emmerz6949/employee-directory
Deployed Site: https://emmerz6949.github.io/employee-directory/

Description: An employee directory React application that allows users to sort the employees alphabetically and reverse alphabetically by first name via the up and down arrow heads beside the word "Name", and to filter the employees by first name, last name, or email via the search bar.

Workout Tracker

GitHub Repository: https://github.com/Emmerz6949/workout-tracker

Deployed Site: https://frozen-plains-71922.herokuapp.com/

Description: A workout tracker application that lets users start a new workout or continue the most recent previous workout via storing and retrieving the workout information in the MongoDB "workouts" collection of the "workout" database. Users can use the "Dashboard" tab to view line graphs and pie charts of all the workout information submitted so far.

REÇQUE

GitHub Repository: https://github.com/Emmerz6949/recipeproject/
Deployed Site: https://emmerz6949.github.io/recipeproject/

Description: A recipe application that allows users to search for recipes based on allergy or dietary restriction. This was a team project; I was responsible for utilizing JavaScript and jQuery to create click events that swap assets and store data into local storage.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- Handled and responded to inbound and outbound calls, chats, and tickets.
- Operated the Kayako ticket system, the Olark chat system, and the Gorgias ticket/chat system.
- Assisted store-front employees with in-store customers.
- Managed the company's Instagram and Facebook through posts, pictures, and videos.
- Created videos of new products to upload to the company's YouTube.
- Utilized Shopify and its inventory system.
- Updated product descriptions and titles on the company's website.

3Play Media Transcript Editor

February 2019 – May 2019 Remote/Maryland

- Demonstrated strong attention to detail while reviewing the desired content to be transcribed and while editing any pre-existing transcription to completely match their related content word for word.
- Consistently met the deadlines for each transcription.

Breakout Games Game Master

October 2017 – March 2019 Columbia, Maryland

- Communicated clues and rules effectively and concisely to guests based on the kind of guests in the rooms.
- Trained new hires on how to effectively and concisely communicate clues and rules to guests.
- Documented guests' waiver information.

Black Rocket Productions Lead Instructor/Assistant Instructor

December 2017 - August 2018 Columbia, Marland

- Instructed children of ages 8 14 on various technology-based courses such as video game design, level design, and programming.
- Created and managed student accounts.
- Maintained confidentiality of students' health records and personal information.
- Used Microsoft Office applications to document student payment information as well as to document hours worked.

Chick-fil-A Cashier/Team Member

October 2014 - April 2017 Columbia, Maryland

- Demonstrated excellent customer service by repeatedly achieving a top seller status during promotional events.
- Duties included operating the cashier, preparing beverages, and stocking supplies.
- Assisted with the new hire training program.
- Routinely relied on by managers to fill shifts.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Developer Certificate - Johns Hopkins Whiting School of Engineering May 2020 - November 2020

 Gained proficiency in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Command Line, Git, and more.

Cyberjutsu Girls Academy

January 2014 - June 2014

 Developed a web page using HTML and CSS & Assembled a computer and became familiar with various computer components.